# BRANDON JACKSON, MBA, PMP, CSM

www.linkedin.com/in/brandonljackson23 • (801) 800-3511 • BrandonLJackson23@gmail.com

#### **EXECUTIVE SUMMARY**

An experienced product manager, who can lead cross-functional teams to build products that customers love. A visionary, who can bring a product vision to life. An executioner, who can manage the entire product lifecycle from ideation to product roadmap execution to retirement. A dedicated researcher and detailed analyst, who can effectively evaluate new opportunities. A professional, who has a strong technical aptitude and business acumen. An inspiring leader, who can motivate team members and maximize performance. An ambassador, who can serve as an expert and evangelist to both internal and external audiences.

## **BUSINESS SKILLS**

Product Management	Project Management	Agile Software Development
Strategic Planning	Product Lifecycle Management	Process Improvement & Automation
Leadership	Customer Satisfaction	Budget Planning & Cost Control
Cost/Benefit Analysis	Contract Negotiation	Team Facilitator
Quality Assurance	Stakeholder Management	Pragmatic Marketing

## **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

JavaScript JQuery HTML / CSS

MERN JSON SQL

MS Office Adobe Creative Suite JIRA / Confluence

GitLab GitHub

## RELEVANT PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

#### NEXEO HR SOLUTIONS 2018 – Present

**Director of Training & Process** 

- Increased applicant volume by 60% through improved job ad syntax and SEO optimization.
- Increased revenue by 17% by implementing agent KPIs and performance accountability.
- Reduced company liability through standardized hiring procedure and internal compliance audits.
- Authored company policy and procedure resulting in improved operational efficiency.
- Oversaw multiple high-profile projects including companywide software implementations and integrations.
- Developed and oversaw the execution of companywide marketing initiatives.
- Supervised a team of 20+ employees across 10 office locations.

## **SECURITYTRAX, AN ALARM.COM COMPANY**

2016 - 2018

**Product Manager** 

- Led a cross-function team to design and build a new user-friendly, modernized, responsive software interface from scratch that customers love
- Implemented Scrum and Kanban software development methodologies from scratch
- Developed and executed a 'Go to Market' strategy to increase awareness and adoption of the new product version

- Designed and implemented a new scalable pricing model centered around customer value to increase adoption and expand into untapped markets
- Implemented new metrics to measure, report and increase customer satisfaction and product success
- Implemented a new communication avenue for distributing and gathering critical information from customers and improve satisfaction

# **CERTIPORT, A PEARSON VUE BUSINESS**

2012 - 2016

**Product Manager** 

- Managed multiple multi-million-dollar online certification programs for high profile clients like Microsoft, Adobe and Autodesk
- Led a cross-functional software development team to successfully build and release hundreds of certification exams on-time and within budget that meet client requirements
- Developed and executed a global product growth strategy
- Worked closely marketing to develop and execute a marketing strategy to promote and position products to ensure optimal success
- Consistently achieved annual revenue growth targets
- Designed and implemented a new global pricing strategy
- Improved NSAT and NPS scores for each program managed
- Managed the full product life cycle for multiple certification programs
- Developed and executed a global growth strategy

Photoshop, Illustrator, InDesign

- Managed multiple simultaneous high-profile IT projects
- Analyzed and recommended new market opportunities

#### **EDUCATION**

UNIVERSITY OF UTAH	Oct 2020
Full-Stack Web Development Bootcamp	
UNIVERSITY OF UTAH	Aug 2012
MBA: Emphasis in Information Systems	
BRIGHAM YOUNG UNIVERSITY	Dec 2007
BS: Exercise Science	
CERTIFICATIONS	
PROJECT MANAGEMENT PROFESSIONAL	Nov 2012
CERTIFIED SCRUM MASTER	Feb 2017
MICROSOFT OFFICE MASTER	Sep 2012
Word, Excel, PowerPoint, Outlook, OneNote, SharePoint, Office 365	
ADOBE CERTIFIED ASSOCIATE	May 2013